Guide to the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, Student Affairs, 1963-present UPG.RG.38
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, Student Affairs
1963-present
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
UPG.RG.38
5 boxes
Administrative Records of the Student Affairs of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, 1963-present.
Access Restrictions
Restricted access to Series I and Series VIII to UPG Administrative personnel only.
Custodial History
Transferred from Student Services to the UPG Archives.
Scope and Content Notes
Enrolled Students, First Year Student Convocation, Housing, Orientation, Resident Handbook, See UPG, Student Handbook, Student Directory, Student Health Plan, Student Information Fair, Student Organizations, Student Publications, UPG Resident Directory
See Also
See also: UPG.RG.52 Visual Images. Prints. Student Activities Fair
Student Publications are filed in UPG.RG.50 Publications Series: Serials
UPG Resident Directory from Fall 2006, See: UPG.RG.38 Series: Enrolled Students [University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg]
See also: UPG.RG.02.4 Ser.: Resource File for "We Made No Small Plans: A Memoir".
Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Greensburg -- Records and correspondence; Universities and colleges -– Pennsylvania -– Greensburg -– Administration; University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
- Enrolled Students [University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg], 2006-2010; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Fall 2071 [Fall 2006] [Restricted Access]
  Fall 2084 [Fall 2007] [Restricted Access]
  Spring 2084 [Spring 2008] [Restricted Access]
  Spring 2094 [Spring 2009] [Restricted Access]
  STRM [Spring 2010] [Restricted Access]
  Access Restrictions
  Access restricted to UPG Administrative Personnel.
  - Enrolled Students [University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg], 2006-2010 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 3)
- First Year Student Convocation [Freshman Convocation], 1997-present; II.
  1997, August 25 [First Freshman Convocation]
  1998, August 27
  1999, August 26
  2000, August 24
  2001, August 23
  2002, August 22
  2003, August 21
  2004, August 26 [First-Year Student Convocation] [changed name from Freshman Convocation]
  2005, August 25
  2006, August 24
  2007, August 23
  2008, August 21
  2009, August 27
  2010, August 26
  2011, August 25
  2012, August 23
  2013, August 22
  2014, August 21
  2015, August 27
  2016, August 25
  2017, August 24
  2018, August 23
  2019, August 22
  - First Year Student Convocation [Freshman Convocation], 1997-present (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 3)
- Housing, 2009; III.
  Pamphlet: "University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Housing. 2009 Room Selection Guide".
  - Housing, 2009 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 4)
- Orientation, 1997-present; IV.
  S.O.A.R. [Student Orientation and Registration; Summer Orientation Academic Registration]
  Parent Schedule [Parent/Guardian Schedule; Guest Schedule]
  June 12 - 13, July 10-11, July 31-Aug. 1, 1997
  July 9-10, August 6-7, 1998
  June 10-11, June 24-25, July 8-9, August 5-6, 1999
  June 8-9, 22-23, July 13-14, 2000
  June 14-15, June 28-29, July 12-13, July 26-27, 2001
  June 13-14, June 27-28, July 11-12, July 25-26, 2002
  June 26-27, July 10-11, July 24-25, 2003
  June 10-11, June 24-25, July 8-9, July 22-23, 2004
  June 9-10, June 23-24, July 21-22, 2005
  June 8-9, 22-23, July 20-21, 2006
  June 14-15, 28-29, July 12-13, 26-27, 2007
  June 12-13, 26-27, July 10-11, 24-25, 2008
  June 11-12, 25-26, July 9-10, 23-24, 2009
  June 10-11, 24-25, July 8-9, 22, 2010
  June 9-10, 23-24, July 7-8, 21-22, 2011
  June 14-15, 28-29, July 12-13, July 26-27, 2012
  June 13-14, 27-28, July 25-26, 2013
  June 12-13, June 26-27, July 10-11, July 24-25, 2014
  June 11-12, June 25-26, July 9-10, July 23-14, 2015
  June 9-10, June 23-24, July 7-8, 21-22, 2016
  June 8-9, June 22-23, July 6-7, July 20-21, 2017
  June 14-15, July 12-13, July 26-27, 2018
  June 13-14, June 27-28, July 11-12, July 25-26, 2019
  Student Schedule
  June 11-12, July 10-11, July 31-Aug. 1, 1997
  [lacks June 8-9], June 22-23, July 31-Aug. 1, 2000
  June 11-12, June 25-26, July 9-10, July 23-24, 2015
  June 23-24, July 21-22, 2022
  Transfer Student Schedule July 13-14, 2000
  Fall Orientation 1999, Aug. 26-29 2000, Aug. 23-25
  Welcome Week 2001
  - Orientation, 1997-present (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 4)
- Resident Handbook, University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, 2001-2003; V.
  2001-2002 2002-2003 and thereafter included as section of Student Handbook
  - Resident Handbook, University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, 2001-2003 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 4)
- SEE UPG, 1998; VI.
  SEE UPG Supporting & Enhancing Your Education At UPG.
  First issued, September, 1998. [Magazine specifically designed for freshmen and incoming students by students. Funded by the Office for Student Affairs]
  Holdings: [Sept., 1998]
  - SEE UPG, 1998 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 4)
- Student Handbook [Student Handbook and Planner], 1973-2019; VII.
  1973-74
  1974-75 1977-78 1979-80 1982-83
  1983-84 1984-85 1986-87 1987-88 1988-89 1989-90
  1990-91
  1991-92
  1992-93
  1993-94
  1994-95
  1995-96
  1996-97
  1997-98
  1998-99
  1999-2000
  2000-2001 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook)
  2001-2002 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook)
  2002-2003 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook)
  2003-2004 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook)
  2004-2005 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook)
  2005-2006 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook)
  2006-2007 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook)
  2007-2008 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook)
  2008-2009 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook)
  2009-2010 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook) [Note: With academic year 2009/10, the Student Handbook available in an electronic edition. UPG Archives has print version of the electronic edition.]
  2010-2011 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook) [Print version of electronic edition.]
  2018-2019 (includes Student Code of Conduct & Judicial Procedures and Resident Handbook) [Print version of electronic edition.]
  - Student Handbook [Student Handbook and Planner], 1973-2019 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 6, Box 5)
- Student Directory, 1963-1974; VIII.
  1963, Fall. [Print copy from UPG Archives UPG.RG.07 Registrar. Series: Class Schedules [Microfilm Edition] Fall 1963-Winter 1970-71.] [Directory has an attachment, "Fall Trimester 1963 Grades", and that attachment should be considered Confidential with access restricted to UPG Administrative Personnel.]
  1973/74 Fall Term Freshmen
  1973/74 Fall Term Sophomore
  - Student Directory, 1963-1974 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 5)
- Student Health Plan [UPMC Student Health Plan], 2008-2009; IX.
  - Student Health Plan [UPMC Student Health Plan], 2008-2009 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 4)
- Student Information Fair [Student Activities Fair; Luau; New Student Information Fair], 2000-2017; X.
  2000-2006, 2008-2010, 2012-2017
  See Also
  See also: UPG.RG.52 Visual Images. Prints. Student Activities Fair
  - Student Information Fair [Student Activities Fair; Luau; New Student Information Fair], 2000-2017 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 4)
- Student Organizations, 1982-present; XI.
  - National Interfraternity Conference, 1982; 1.
    Ltr. dtd. 10/8/82 to Donald L. Stohl, Ex. Sec., Kappa Delta Rho, Inc. outlining some guiding principles and includes a "Resolution Against Hazing". [Ltr. found within some faculty files of Dr. Donald Gibson. faz 5/21/15.]
    - National Interfraternity Conference, 1982 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 7)
  - Guide to Student Organizations, 1999-2017; 2.
    [Rosters] 1999/2000 (?), 2000/2001 Brochure. "Guide to Student Organizations" [undtd] Pamphlet. "Guide of Organizations. GO! University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg" 26 p. [Fall, 2007] [Pamphlet] "SGA Club Handbook" (revised August 2007) 12 p. [Listing of student organizations appearing on the University of Pittsburgh Greensburg Webpage: Student Life. Getting Involved. [2/21/2017]] [faz]
    - Guide to Student Organizations, 1999-2017 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 7)
  - Historical Note, 2017; 3.
    Scope and Contents Notes
    As of 2017 the following organizations either existed or had existed on the UPG campus:
    Student Government Association (SGA)
    Activities Board (AB)
    Entertainment Committee
    Film Committee
    Lecture Committee
    Mixer Committee
    On-stage Committee
    Publicity Committee
    Special Events Committee
    University Liaison Committee
    Accounting Club See also: Pitt-Greensburg Accounting/Business Club
    Active Minds
    Allies [Allies/LGBT]
    Alpha Alpha Delta (UPG Chapter of Sigma Tau Delta) [International English Honor Society] SEE: Sigma Tau Delta
    Alpha Phi Sigma
    Alpha Epsilon Kappa (UPG Chapter of Pi Sigma Alpha)
    Alpha Phi Sigma (Criminal Justice Honor Society)
    Alpha Psi Omega
    American Sign Language Club
    Alpha Phi Sigma [National Honor Society in Criminal Justice]
    Amnesty International Committee. UPG Chapter
    Anthropology Club
    Archaeological Society
    Asian Cultures Club
    Ben Franklin Society
    Beta Beta Beta (National Honor Soc. in Biology). UPG Chapter
    Biology Club
    Black Cultural Society [UPG Black Cultural Society]
    Black Student Union [BSU]
    Bobcat Dancers
    Bowling Club
    Brothers and Sisters in Christ (B.A.S.I.C.)
    Bushido
    Business Honors Society (BHS)
    Campus Campaign For Free Thought
    Campus Ministry
    Catholic Newman Club
    Chess Club
    Chi Alpha Sigma (National College Athlete Honor Society). UPG Chapter
    Children's Literature Club [ UPG Children's Literature Club]
    Chinese Club
    Christian Fellowship
    Circle K International
    College Action Sports Club
    College Democrats
    College Republicans
    Communication Honor Society See: Lambda Pi Eta
    Computer Club
    Concert Choir
    Construction Architecture Design Engineering Club
    Creative Writing Club [organized 2017] [Creative and Professional Writing Majors]
    Criminal Justice Society [Criminal Justice Club; Upsilon Psi Gamma]
    Da Vinci Scholars Organization
    Debate Club
    Delta Eta Beta [Village Senate]
    Delta Psi Omega [National Theatre Honor Society]
    Diversity Student Coalition
    Drama Club SEE: RG52 Subject Files. Ser.: UPG Players; RG52 Ser.: UPG Performance Collective
    Engineering Society: Engineering Club (For photo, See: qRG60 Prints.)
    Environmental and Ecology Club [Environmental Society; Environmental Club]
    Ethnological Adventure Society
    French Club
    Frisbee Club
    Game Creation Organization
    Gamma Sigma Epsilon [Chemistry Honors Society]
    Gay and Lesbian Outreach Coalition (GLOC) See also: Allies/LGBT
    Gay/Straight Alliance See: Pitt-Greensburg Gay/Straight Alliance
    Gender Issues Group
    German Society of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
    Habitat for Humanity. UPG Chapter
    Health & Rehabilitation Sciences Club
    History Club
    Hope 4 Africa
    Humanities Society of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
    Humans vs. Zombies [Club]
    Ice Hockey Club [Pitt-Greensburg Ice Hockey team; Bobcat Ice Hockey Team]
    Intramurals
    International Club
    Judicial Board, University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
    Kappa Phi Sigma
    Lambda Pi Eta [Communication Honor Society]
    Lingua Franca
    Math Club
    Men Against Sexual Violence [MASV] See: RG52 Men Against Sexual Violence [MASV]
    Middle Eastern Club
    Minority Student Coalition
    NAGPODP (Non Affiliated Group Pondering Ongoing Diversifying Problems)
    The Nerdfighters
    Organization for Black Awareness (OBA)
    Out Doors Club
    Outdoor Adventure and Community Service (OACS)
    Pendulum
    Performing Arts Society
    Perspective
    Phi Eta Sigma [National Freshman Honor Society]. UPG Chapter.
    Phi Kappa Phi [National Seniors Honor Society] Chapter 286 [UPG Chapter]
    Philosophy Club
    Photography Club [Pitt-Greensburg Photography Club]
    Pi Gamma Mu [National Honor Society in Social Science]
    Pi Mu Epsilon [National Mathematics Honor Society]
    Pi Sigma Alpha [National Political Science Honor Society]
    Pitt-Greensburg Accounting/Business Club
    Pitt-Greensburg College Democrats
    Pitt Greensburg Student Alumni Association (SAA) See: Student Alumni Association (SAA)
    Pitt Greensburg Alumni Association (SAA) See: Student Alumni Association (SAA)
    Pitt-Greensburg Band
    Pitt-Greensburg Gay/Straight Alliance
    Pitt Increases Volunteer Opportunities Today (PIVOT)
    Pre-Law Society
    Psi Chi (National Honor Society in Psychology)
    Psychology Club
    Radio Station Club
    Rainbow Coalition of UPG [reactivated under new name: Allies]
    Resident Student Council
    Rotoract Club
    Rotary Club of UPG
    SALUTE Veterans Honor Society [2019- ] See RG52 Ser.: SALUTE Veterans Honor Society
    Science Club
    Senior Honor Society [University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Senior Honor Society] SEE: Phi Kappa Phi. Chapter 286.
    Sigma Alpha Lambda SEE: Society of Success [UPG]
    Sigma Tau Delta [International English Honor Society]
    Ski Club
    Snowcats Ski Club
    Social Science Honor Society
    Society of Success [UPG] [Society of Leadership and Success] [Sigma Alpha Lambda]
    Spanish Club
    Student Alumni Association (SAA) [Pitt Greensburg Student Alumni Association (SAA)]
    Student Athlete Advisory Council [Student Athlete Advisory Committee]
    Student Health Advisory Committee (SHAC)
    Student Health Advisory Council
    Students PSEA [Students Pa. State Education Association] [UPG Chapter]
    Students for Peace and Justice [Students for Peace]
    UPG Children's Literature Club See: Children's Literature Club
    UPG Collegiate Chorale See RG52 Subject Files--UPG Collegiate Chorale
    UPG Concert Band See RG52 Subject Files--UPG Concert Band
    UPG Habitat for Humanity
    UPG Performance Collective SEE RG52 Subject Files. Ser.: UPG Performance Collective
    UPG Players
    UPG Young Democrats [College Democrats]
    Upsilon Psi Gamma Chapter of the Lambda Alpha Epsilon Criminal Justice Assoc.[Criminal Justice Society]
    Video Game Affinity Club
    Village Senate See: Delta Eta Beta
    Visual Arts Society
    Writers Club
    Yoga Club
    Young Democratic Socialists (YDS)
    The researcher should consult the various editions of the Student Handbook for information on the student organizations which are listed above. In addition, the UPG Archives has information in a separate file on the following organizations:
    Activities Board. Film Committee
    Activities Board [Student Activities Board]
    Alpha Alpha Delta SEE: Sigma Tau Delta
    Athletic Club
    Beta Beta Beta (National Honor Society in Biology). UPG Chapter
    Chi Alpha Sigma (National College Athlete Honor Soc.) UPG Chapter
    Children's Literature Club [UPG Children's Literature Club]
    Drama Club SEE: RG52 Ser.: UPG Players; RG52 Ser.: UPG Performance Collective
    Gay/Straight Alliance See: Pitt-Greensburg Gay/Straight Alliance See also: Allies/LGBT
    German Society
    Lambda Pi Eta
    Organization For Black Awareness
    Pre Law Society See: UPG.RG.38 Student Affairs. Series: Student Organizations for poster calendar, "The Pre Law Society presents...Women of UPG 1993".
    Psi Chi
    Rainbow Coalition of UPG [reactivated under the name: Allies]
    Sigma Alpha Lambda See: Society of Success [UPG]
    Sigma Tau Delta
    Student Government Association
    Student Health Advisory Committee
    Student PSEA [Student Pa. State Education Association]
    Students For Peace and Justice [Students for Peace]
    University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Senior Honor Society [Senior Honor Society] [est.2000 evolved in 2013 as Phi Kappa Phi Chapter 286.]
    UPG Players SEE: RG52 Ser.: UPG Players
    For graduates inducted into campus honorary societies, See: UPG.RG.07 Series: Graduation [Commencement] Programs.
    - Historical Note, 2017 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 7)
- Student Publications, XII.
  Beginnings
  Perspective: The Official Student News Magazine of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
  Perspectives: The Official Student News Magazine of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
  Transition UPG: A Magazine for Incoming Students
  UPG Magazine: A Magazine for incoming Students
  Twin Lakes Review
  See UPG.RG.50 Publications Series: Serials
  - Student Publications (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 4)
- UPG Resident Directory [UPG Resident Phone Directory], 1995-2005; XIII.
  From Fall 2006, See: UPG.RG.38 Series: Enrolled Students [University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg]
  For a listing of students at the UPG Campus, See also: UPG.RG.70.2 UPO DOC TELE, University of Pittsburgh Phone Directory.
  Holdings:
  1995 Fall Term 96-1
  1996 Spring Term 96-2
  1997, January-April
  1998, January-April, August-December
  1999, January-April, September-December
  2000, January-April
  2000, Fall
  2001, Jan. 15, Jan. 26
  2001, Fall [Oct., 2001]
  2002, Spring
  2002, Sept. 10
  2003, Sept. 8
  2004, Aug. 30
  2005, Aug. 27
  - UPG Resident Directory [UPG Resident Phone Directory], 1995-2005 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 9, Box 4)